我们注定在你的阴影中无法逃离  --"海地传说"
你确定要自己拿着这个吗？不要勉强自己。
Huh? You sure you got that? Don't strain yourself.
好了，钥匙还给我
Well, that's it.Turned in my key.
好，但不是现在
Yep. No turning back now.
你还认为这是个好主意吗？
You still think this is a good idea?
什么？我开车这事？
What, me driving this thing?
告诉你，我更乐意让你来开
I told you,I'm more than happy to let you drive.
不，我是说你陪我一起搬走
No, this,moving in with you.
一起有了这个宝贝
Having this baby.
Jessie，遇见你就是发生在我身上最美好的事
Jessie, you're the best thing that ever happened to me.
我为今天已经准备很久了
I've been ready for this for a long time.
突然想起一个怪异的梦，昨晚做的
I just remembered the weirdest dream I had last night.
这是最后的机会清除它
It's the last chance  to remove it.
再多吸一点，我看不见任何东西
A little more suction，please. Can't see a thing in there.
是头骨，那个人的一块头骨
It's skull.It's part of the guy's skull.
你的股骨断裂
Intertrochanteric fracture in your hip.
左边锁骨和三根肋骨碎了
Your left clavicle and three ribs are shattered.
左右小腿胫骨均已骨折
You've got compound fractures in your right and left tibia.
好消息是，你还能行走
Good news is you will walk again
在3或4个月的疗养之后
within three or four months of therapy.
我的孩子呢？
My baby?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们知道这很漫长，Jessie
I know it's been a long haul for you, Jessie.
但我们还是需要派个理疗师去你家
But we'll still need to send a physical therapist to you at home.
有人来接你吗？你父亲还是母亲？
Can someone come pick you up?Your mother or father?
呃，我母亲在我还是婴儿的时候就死于癌症
Uh, my mom died of cancer when I was a baby,
而我父亲在母亲死后就把我交给姑姑收养
and my father gave me to my aunt to be raised after my mom died.
我已经有一年没见过他了
I haven't seen him in years.
Laurent小姐，他能来这接你吗？
Miss Laurent,can he come here to pick you up?
爸？
Dad?
爸，谢谢你来接我
Thanks for picking me up, Dad.
恩，高兴能够帮到你
Hmm. Glad I could help.
你男朋友的事我很遗憾
Sorry about your boyfriend.
这是你母亲的房间，你就住这吧
This was your mother's room.You're gonna have to stay in here.
其它的卧室要上楼
The other bedrooms are upstairs.
我帮你上床
Let's get you in bed.
你的姑姑过世后，他们给了你一些东西
When your aunt passed away, they gave me some things you had there.
衣服
Clothes.
饿吗？我给你做个三明治什么的。
You hungry?I could make you a sandwich or something.
呃...
Uh...
不用了，我不饿，只是有点累
No, I'm fine.Just tired is all.
哦，对了，这水龙头出来的水有时候有点脏
Oh, yeah,the water out of the tap sometimes comes out bad.
稍微等它流一会儿就干净了
You just let it run a little,it'll clear up.
Preston（照片里男人的名字）
Preston.
爸？
Dad?
你在吗？
You here?
哦,老天!
Oh, my word.
妈妈，谢谢你
Thank you, Mama.
给Jessabelle，生日快乐，我爱你
你好, Jessabelle.
Hello, Jessabelle.
妈妈
Mom.
我犹豫了很久
I went back and forth 100 times
无论录这些录影带
whether or not this was a good idea.
是不是个好主意
Making these tapes.
而结果如你所见，我在这
But as you can see,here I am.
现在是1988年3月14
It is March 14,and it is 1988,
我怀了你7个月
and I am seven months pregnant with you.
我爱你Jessabelle，我爱你
I love you, Jessabelle. I love you.
如果你正在看这个
If you're watching this,
那意味着我已经走了
it means I'm gone.
但不想因为我，让今天成为伤感的一天
But I don't want this to be a day of sadness.
我想因为我，让今天成为开心的一天
I want it to be a day of happiness.
所以不想谈我的事
So I'm not even gonna talk about me.
只有一件事情是重点
The only thing that's important
就是我爱你
is that you know that I love you.
还有我一直照看着你，一直
And that I have been watching over you, always.
好了，胡扯够了
Okay. So, enough of that sad shit.
我告诉过你爸爸，希望他
I told your father that I wanted him
把这个带子在你18岁生日时给你
to give you this tape on your 18th birthday.
所以对你而言是2006年
So for you,it is 2006.
生日快乐！生日快乐，宝贝！
Happy Birthday!Happy Birthday, baby!
我想过买一个蛋糕
I thought about having a cake,
但把这一切向Davis夫人解释的话
but explaining all this to Mrs. Davis
有点太不可思议
just would have been a little too weird.
呃，Davis夫人，是我们的厨师
Uh, Mrs. Davis is our cook,
如果她还在我们家，代我转达问候
and if she's there could you tell her I said hi?
她人很好，但这还是可能吓坏她了
She's so sweet.That ought to freak her out, though.
她很怕鬼
She is scared of ghosts.
Whoo-oo-oo!
总而言之，我想录这个
Anyway, um, I wanted to make this tape
是因为想让你了解我
because I wanted you to get to know me.
我想给你一个生日礼物
And I wanted to give you a birthday gift,
一盒作为生日读物的牌
a birthday reading with my cards.
我真的很擅长这个
I am really good at this.
我就知道
I'm always right.
没法弄断包装，所以必须得这样
You can't cut the deck,so this will have to do.
好了
Here we go.
我还留着你的手镯，妈妈
I still have your bracelet, Mom.
好.这个是"死亡"
Okay. So this is Death.
但它不意味死亡，它意味着转变
But it doesn't mean "death" death.It means transition.
而今年，你18岁
And this year,your 18th year,
将是变化的一年
is gonna be a year of transition.
你知道它的预言是什么？它说你不会离开圣弗朗西斯
You know what it says here? It says that you've never left St. Francis
而且你永远不会离开
and that you're never gonna leave.
宝贝，你得离开这去看更大的世界
Baby, you've gotta get out there and see the world.
外面有很多精彩
There's so much great stuff out there.
套杯，水相牌，水代表务实
Suits of Cups.That's the water sign,and water is pragmatic.
意味着你会比较顺利
It goes the way of least resistance.
但这有太多水了啊
But this is a lot of water.
你是不是做游泳相关的工作，或者经常出海之类的？
Are you a swimmer,or do you do something with the sea?
我根本不会游泳
I can't even swim.
你是个宅女，像妈妈一样
You're a homebody,just like your mama.
又错了，大错特错
Wrong again.You're terrible at this!
好，这上面说你并不孤单
Well, it says here that you're not alone.
有个灵魂在家里与你同在
That there is a presence in the house with you.
这不是坏事，到处有守护者或天使
It's not a bad thing.There are guardian angels everywhere.
也许就是我
Maybe I'm seeing me.
啊!
Uh!
对，是女性
Yes, so she's a she.It's a female.
嗯...
Um...
她希望你离开这所房子
She wants you out of the house.
她说这房子是她的
She says it's hers.
天啊，爸爸！你吓坏我了！
Jesus, Dad!You scared the shit out of me!
从哪找到这个？
Where did you get that?
回答这该死的问题
I asked you a goddamn question!
我问“从哪找到的？”
I said, "Where didyou get that?"
在妈妈的房间
I found it in my room,in Mom's room.
别，爸爸，别！你在干什么？
Don't, Dad! Don't!What are you doing?
爸，你在干什么？
Dad, what are you doing?
哦！不，爸爸.哦.天啊,爸爸
Oh! No, Dad.Oh, God, Dad.
别多管闲事
No more snooping around.
爸爸？爸爸？
Dad? Dad?
爸爸
Dad.
爸爸！
Dad!
爸爸
Dad.
你应该睡觉了，甜心
It's past your bedtime,sweetie.
有个灵魂在家里与你同在
That there is a presence in the house with you.
你是谁？
Who are you?
Jessabelle.
我做了早餐
I made breakfast.
昨晚的事我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry about last night.
当时有点喝多了，以后不会再这样了
I was a little drunk.It's not gonna happen again.
没事
It's all right.
那是你母亲用过的旧轮椅
That was your mother's old chair.
一直放在外面的仓库
It was out in the shed.
没想到你母亲在最后一夜
Didn't expect to see your mother last night.
录了那盒录像带
That tape,I didn't know she made that tape,
但她确实录了
that she actually went through with it.
你只找到一盒录像带？
You just found that one tape?
恩，就一盒
Uh-huh, just one.
你好, Jessabelle.
Hello, Jessabelle.
我爱你.
I love you.
我也爱你，妈妈
I love you too, Mom.
离我们上次看牌已经3个星期了
It's been three weeks since our last reading.
有太多费解的事了，所以我问了Moses
There was so much weird stuff in there,so I asked Moses about it.
不是那个十诫Moses（圣经人物）
Not Ten Commandments Moses,
而是我朋友，来自Jerry's Creek教堂的Moses
but my friend Moses from my churchon Jerry's Creek.
别告诉爸爸，他会杀了我
Don't tell Dad.He'd kill me.
Moses教了我该怎么读牌
Moses taught me how to read cards.
我给他看了你的内容，他说了些有意思的话
So I showed him your reading,and he said something interesting.
他说家里有两个灵魂，2个女性
He said that the two presences in the house,the two females,
它们都是你
they're both you.
你做噩梦了对吗？
You've been having nightmares, right?
你看到的灵魂受伤了，对吗？
And when you see,it this presence,it's broken, right?
它是个恶魔，但那只是心魔
It's a demon,but it's an inner demon.
你肯定发生过事故之类的
You were in some sort of accident or something,
或者是你看见谁发生过
or maybe somebody you know was.
听我说，那不是你的错
Now, I want you to listen to me.It wasn't your fault.
不要再自责，那不是你的错，好吗？
Stop blaming yourself, sweetheart.It wasn't your fault. Okay?
我们看看最后一张牌的内容
Now that we know that's what that last reading meant...
我意思是Moses说的最后一张牌
I mean, that's what Moses says.
我们抽一张新牌
So, we're gonna get you a new one.
好了
All right.
"死亡"，那意味转变，你不用担心
Death. That means transition.You really don't have to worry about that.
我看见了非常恐怖的死亡
I see a very horrible death.
爸？
Dad?
Laurent小姐?
Miss Laurent?
我敲过门了，但是我知道你用轮椅不方便
I was knocking,but I know you're in a wheelchair,
所以我直接进来了
so I got in.
嗨，叫我Jessie就好了
Hi. It's just Jessie.
呃，医院跟你说过我会来吧？
Uh, the hospital told you I was coming, right?
呃，没.嗯~有，有
Uh, no.Um, yes. Yes.
哦
Oh.
你就是Arlenna小姐吧
You must be Miss Arlenna.
Rosaura.你可以叫我Rosaura
Rosaura.You can call me Rosaura.
很开心见到你
It's great to meet you.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
你感觉还好吗？
Okay. Okay.You feel good?
我一会儿再来，好吗？
I'll be back and check on you, okay?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
No, no!
这他妈怎么了？
What the hell's going on?
冷静一下，静下来
Just calm down.Settle down.
这儿没什么，什么也没有
It's nothing. It's nothing.
你他妈去哪了？啊？
Where the hell were you? Huh?
抱歉，非常抱歉，Laurent先生，我只是离开了5分钟
I'm sorry.I'm so sorry, Mr. Laurent.It was only five minutes.
马上滚！
Get out! Now.
-对不起    -滚！
-I'm sorry.-Get out!
爸爸，你说的“什么也没有”是什么意思？没有什么？
What did you mean by "nothing", Dad?What's nothing?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
就是这该死的录影带！
It's her goddamn tapes!
她已经吓到你了.我早告诉她不要录
She's got you scared out of your mind.I told her not to do this.
爸爸，这是妈妈.这是我唯一感受她的方式！
But, Dad, it's Mom.It's all I have of her!
那些在带子里的东西，根本不是你妈妈.
That thing on these tapes is not your mother.
她怀孕5周后
Five weeks into her pregnancy,
在她大脑里发现肿瘤
we found out she had tumors in her brain.
她不愿意化疗.没什么能救她.
She wouldn't do chemo.Nothing to help herself.
癌症影响了她的心智，这根本不是她.
It ate her mind, the cancer.It just wasn't her anymore.
但是，爸爸，我想看！
But, Dad, I want to watch them!
为什么？好让她继续引起你更多恐慌？
Why? So she can scare the shit out of you some more?
-我要烧了这些带子             -爸爸，别！
-I'm gonna burn these tapes.  -Dad, no!
-不，爸爸！ -别,爸爸！爸爸！
-No, Dad!   -Don't, Dad! Dad!
爸爸
Dad.
哦，天啊！
Oh, God!
爸爸！爸爸！
Dad! Dad!
Jessie!
不！爸爸！
No! Dad!
爸爸！
Dad!
再见，Leon,愿你的灵魂得以安息.阿门
Goodbye, Leon. May your soul finally find peace. Amen.
嘿，Jessie.
Hey, Jessie.
Preston.
过的怎么样？
How you been?
呃
Uh...
真是个傻问题.
That was a really stupid question.
上周，听说你回来了
I heard you were in town last week.
本来想过来，但觉得应该先打个电话个你
I would have come over,but I figured I should call first.
我试着给你打了几分钟，都没人接
I tried you a few times, but no one picked up.
抱歉，我爸爸的电话在楼上.
I'm sorry.My Dad's phone is upstairs,
应该还有好几周都不会有人接
and it's gonna be a few more weeks
直到我能走上楼
before I can walk upstairs to answer it.
好吧，我很抱歉
Right. I'm sorry.
能见到你真好,Preston.
It's really good to see you, Preston.
我也很开心见到你
It's good to see you, too.
你父亲的事我很遗憾
I'm really sorry  about your dad.
Jessie?
Jessie, 你还好吗?
Jessie, you okay?
嘿
Hey.
早
Morning.
早上好
Good morning.
呃
Uh...
你在这待了一个晚上？
You stayed here all night?
是，我觉得要确保你没事
Yeah, well,I figured I'd stick around,make sure you're okay.
谢谢.你不必那样做
Thanks. You didn't have to.
好吧，我该回去了
Well, I guess I should get going home.
很想再见到你
But I'd love to see you again, though.
改天再来
Be okay if I come by some other time?
好的， 我也希望
Yeah. Yeah, I'd like that.
好吧，你自己注意
All right.You take care.
呃，等等
Uh, wait, wait.
别走
Please don't go.
怎么了？
What?
如果没人跟我说话，我会疯的
If I don't talk to somebody, I'm gonna go crazy.
也许我已经疯了
Maybe I already am crazy.
好吧,我哪也不去
Okay. I don't gotta go anywhere.
-就在这里           -谢谢
-I'll stay right here. -Thank you.
但你不觉得我们应该换个地方吗？
But you think we can get the hell out of this place?
这里给我一种毛毛的感觉
Kind of gives me the creeps.
好啊
Yeah.
很好，大家还在这
Pretty much everybody's still here.
Rick Foster才从阿富汗回来，但我想他应该很快要回去了
Rick Foster just got back from Afghanistan.But he's going back, I think.
他仍然是Shawna的丈夫
He's still married to Shawna.
如果我娶了Shawna，我也想快点回去
If I was married to Shawna,I'd be going back, too.
Mary Kimball离了2次婚
Mary Kimball's been married and divorced twice.
-两次？ -她有3个小孩
-Twice? -She's got three kids.
住在采石场新矿场附近
Lives in that new subdivision over by the quarry.
采石场
The quarry.
采石场还在这儿啊？
So, the quarry's still there, huh?
是啊，你知道采石场就是一个超级大洞
Yes, well, you know,it is a big, giant hole.
你没法真的搬走那个大洞
You can't really move a big, giant hole.
自作聪明.少来了
Smart ass. Cut me some slack.
Yeah.
什么都没变，死气沉沉的婚姻和债务更是一成不变
Nothing's changed, really.Marriages and mortgages.
我知道你为什么那么急着出去了
I can see why you couldn't get out fast enough.
呃
Uh...
Preston，我很抱歉
Preston, I'm so sorry.
嘿，你不需要跟我解释
Hey, you don't gotta explain to me.
如果我能上大学，我也会远离这个小镇再也不回来
If I'd gotten into college,I would've left this town and neverlooked back.
永远不会有其它想法。
Never would have given it a second thought.
不是那样的，我其实很想念这个地方
That's not true.I thought about this place a lot.
我也想你，很抱歉没有给你打过电话
I missed you . I'm sorry I didn't call more.
我只是想分得彻底一点，也许
I just wanted a clean breakaway,I guess.
反正我的离开不是因为你
But me leaving never had anything  to do with you.
没事，我理解
It's okay.I understand.
你过得怎么样呢？
How have you been?
结婚了
Married.
哦，呃
Oh, uh...
她怎么想，你昨天晚上没回去的事
Where did she think ，you were last night?
哦，我实话实说
Oh, I told her the truth.
我告诉她，我陪着一个许愿的小孩
I told her I was with a Make-A-Wish kid.
告诉我后来发生了什么
So tell me，what's going on.
你看起来很害怕回到这里
You seemed so scared back there.
嗯，我回来以后一直做噩梦
Um, okay.I've been having nightmares.
我已经做了很多不好的梦
I've been having really bad dreams,
那些梦都如此真实以致我都要疯了
and they're so real that I think I'm going crazy.
我梦见一个女孩，她看起来已经死了
I dreamed  there's this girl.She looks dead,
她想抓住我，然后杀了我
and she's trying to get me, kill me.
还有像是被烧死的男人
And there's this man. It looks like he's been burnt to death,
他看着我的样子 像是我烧死他的一样
and he looks at me like I did it.
好像无论发生了什么，都是我的错
Like whatever happened to him,it was my fault.
你会挺过去的
Well, after everything you've been through,
你以前没做过这样的噩梦，现在却有,不奇怪吗？
it would be weird if you weren't having nightmares, right?
你有没有想过去看心理医生？
Have you thought about seeing a shrink?
我看不起
I can't afford it.
我意思是如果我有钱
I mean, if I had any money at all,
根本不会回来跟爸爸一起生活
I wouldn't have come home to live with Dad.
我身无分文
I'm flat broke.
对了，还有些录影带
And there are these tapes.
现在我们知道最后一张卡牌的寓意了
Now that we know that's what that last reading meant..
我意思是Moses说的最后一张牌
I mean, that's what Moses says.
我们抽一张新牌
So, we're gonna get you a new one.
我真的觉得你不要再看了
I really don't think you should be watching these anymore.
这肯定是你做噩梦的原因
It's no wonder why you're having nightmares.
对你而言没有好处
It's not good for you.
如果这是你的妈妈，你会看吗？
Would you watch them if it was your mom?
如果这是你唯一了解她的方式？
Your only chance to get to know her?
是，我会，但我会等调整好自己生活状态以后再看
Yeah, I would, but I'd wait, wait until I was recuperated.
而不是在这个她死掉的房子里看
Not when I was still stuck in this house where she died.
我是说你这行为很怪
I mean,it's just weird.
而且，她还错得多对得少
And besides, she's wrong more than she's right.
她说你不会离开小镇，你爱游泳
She said you never left town,you love to swim.
她说了爸爸会死
She said Dad was gonna die.
不，她是说你会死
No, she thought you were gonna die.
她说了10件事都错了
She said 10 things that were wrong,
而你偏偏选一条勉强算是对的来说事
and you picked one that was almost right.
Jessie，她没预测你爸爸的死
Jessie, she didn't predict your dad's death.
她认为她看见了你的死
She thought she  saw your death,
她所有事都说错了
and she was wrong about everything.
现在我在想关于你的梦
Now, look, I've been thinking  about your dreams.
那个一直出现的女孩，就是你自己
That girl you keep seeing, it's you.
那个被烧死的男的
And the guy that burnt in the fire,
应该是你在做那场车祸的噩梦
you're having a nightmare about your accident.
妈的，是我老婆，抱歉，我得走了
Shit, that's my wife.I'm sorry,but I've gotta go.
给，这是我的工作电话，上面有我家电话号码
Here. That's my work cell.It's got my home phone number on it.
随时可以打给我，无论白天晚上，好吗？
You call me any time, day or night, all right?
保证？
Promise?
好的
Okay.
抱歉，我真的得走了
I'm sorry. I gotta go.
谢谢你，Preston
Thank you, Preston.
应该的，自己保重
Yeah, of course.Now you take care.
这是美丽的路易斯安那南部
This is beautiful South Louisiana.
这是路易斯安那南部的美女
And here is the belle of South Louisiana.
没错，她我准备许配给Hugh Hefner先生的美女
That's right. Here she is I'm gonna send this to Mr. Hugh Hefner,
我要用这录影带赚些外块
and I'm gonna make me some money on the side.
南路易斯安那州最美的女人的录影带
The most beautiful woman in South Louisiana.
真坏.
Bad.
等等，这是家庭录影.
This is the family portrait. Wait a minute. Wait.
我意思是只发一点给Hugh Hefner先生
I might just send me some tapes to that Mr. Hugh Hefner.
虫子在咬我屁股
These bugs are eating my ass up!
看看脚，它们哪去了？
- Let's see those feet.Where'd they go?
在这里.
There it is.
哦！她在这里.宝贝
Oh! There she is. Baby!
嘿，宝贝，你没法再美了.看这里
Hey, baby, you can't improve perfection.Look at that.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
记录给子孙后代
Recording for posterity.
给那些不记得过去注定是要重蹈覆辙的人
Those who don't remember the past are doomed to repeat it.
好，让我们进入未来，圣诞快乐！
Okay, well, let's go into the future.Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐! 耶!
Merry Christmas! Yeah!
现在我要教你怎么用它
Now, listen,I want to show you how to use it.
你只需要拿起来，按下这个然后拍摄就可以了
You just take it, point it, and shoot it.
会了吗？，好的会了吗？拿起来
You got it?Okay, you got it?Just hold it
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
Davis夫人，我觉得这些人已经准备开始吃东西了
Mrs. Davis, I think these people are about ready to eat.
如果还不让他们坐下并且吃东西的话
They're gonna eat the furniture
他们就要吃掉家具了
if we don't sit them down and feed them.
我要开始了
I'm gonna do the thing.
What? Okay.
我们开始吧
Let's work with this, okay?
抱歉，在你打开礼物之前
Excuse me.Before you unwrap the presents and get into some funky music,
我还要占用点时间吹嘘下
I just wanted to take a little second here to brag about something.
哦，这多不像你啊Leon
Oh, yeah, surprise.How very unlike you, Leon.
稍等，我要集中注意
Now wait a minute.It has come to my attention
这位我深爱着的人，有小孩了
that my lovely,devoted wife is with child.
我怀孕了!
I'm pregnant!
恭喜Leon和Kate
Raise your glasses and toast to Leon and Kate!
-恭喜             -我能喝的
-Congratulations. -I can drink.
你已经死了，Jessabelle.
You're already dead,Jessabelle.
你死定了!
You're already dead!
Preston? 对不起，我说过不会打过来，但....
Preston? I'm sorry. I know I said I wouldn't call, but...
你是谁?
Who is this?
呃
Uh...
我是Jessie，Jessie Laurent.你是谁？
It's Jessie，Jessie Laurent.Who is this?
靠近点.
Come closer.
再近点.
Closer.
很好
Yes.
嘿，你还好吗？
Hey. You all right?
Sam告诉我你昨晚打过来了
Sam just told me you called last night.
没事，对不起
I'm all right.I'm so sorry.
我只是被吓到了
I just got scared.
家里都还正常？
Everything okay at home?
说“很好”是有点过，但至少我没事
Well, "okay" is stretching it a bit,but I'm fine.
我很高兴你在这里
Well, I'm glad you're here.
好吧，告诉我发生了什么
All right. Well, tell me  what happened.
你也看见了？
Oh, you see that, too?
是的
Yeah.
那是什么？
What is that?
我不知道，我觉得是有人在那儿
I don't know. I think somebody's out there.
昨晚那里绝对有人
There was somebody definitely out there last night.
你觉得那条旧船还能用吗？
You think that old boat still works?
当然
Sure.
那到底是什么？
What is that?
嗯，好像是巫术一类的东西
Mmm. Some kind of voodoo or something.
我们这区一半的墓地到处都有这种鬼东西
Half the cemeteries in this parish are full of that kind of shit.
那他们为什么会放在这儿？
But why would they put it on our land?
一定有人来过这里
Yeah, someone's definitely been out here, all right.
而且是不久以前
That's pretty fresh.
怎么了？
What?
下面有东西
There's something down there.
什么东西？
What is that?
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
这不是我第一次下水
This isn't my first time in the bayou.
嗯，这就奇怪了
Hmm. That's weird.
那是我的生日
That's my birthday.
为什么有人要这样吓你？
Why would someone want to spook you like this?
也许那就是个真的墓碑
Or maybe that's  a real gravestone.
也许你有个双胞胎姐妹之类的
Maybe you had a twin sister or something.
我从来就没有什么姐妹，就算有为什么她跟我一样的名字？
I never had a sister.And why would we both have the same name?
不知道，我有两个表兄都叫Beauregards
I don't know.I've got cousins with two Beauregards in their family.
他俩就像名字一样像
They just like the name.
但谁杀了鸡？又是谁把花带了过来？
But who killed that chicken? And who brings flowers?
你不觉得这墓碑下有东西？
Do you think there's something under that stone?
好吧
All right.
回你家看看有什么工具
I guess we'll go back to your house and see what kind of tools you've got.
啊
Uh!
你完全不知道你父母还有另一个小孩？
You don't recall any mention of your parents having another little girl?
嗯
Hmm.
找我们是对的
Well, you were right to call us.
我怀疑这是一个死胎
I suspect it was a stillbirth.
我们会做相关检测
We'll run some tests,
看看他是不是跟你有同样DNA
find out if she was a relative of yours based on your DNA sample.
当然，上次尸检后我们就有了你爸爸的DNA样品
Of course we have a sample of your daddy already from his autopsy.
找到线索会通知你
So we'll give you a call when we find out  who this infant was.
谢谢警官，就知道找你们是对的
Thank you, Sheriff. We knew we had to call you right away.
再提醒我一次，你和Laurent小姐的关系
Remind me again the nature of your relationship  with Miss Laurent.
我们是高中以来的老朋友
We're old friends from high school.
好了，那么晚安
Y'all have a good night, then.
谢谢，警官
Thank you, Sheriff.
你不能再留在这了吧？
You know you can't stay here, right?
我没别的地方去
I've got nowhere  else to go.
不，你有的
Yeah, you do.
-你还好吗？      -恩
You all right?   Yeah.
嘿，亲爱的
Hey, honey.
嘿，Sam这位是Jessie.Jessie这是Sam,我老婆
Hey, Sam, this is Jessie. Jessie, this is Sam, my wife.
现在已经快1点了，我明天还要上班
It's almost 1:00 a.m.I gotta work tomorrow.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
呃，都是我的错，对不起
Um, this is my fault.I'm so sorry.
给你们添麻烦了
I'm the one who dragged him all into this.
我们没有多余的房.希望这个沙发适合你
We don't have an extra room.Hope the couch is okay for you.
没问题
Yeah, it's fine.
我得睡了
I need to get to bed.
谢...
Thank...
不好意思
I'm sorry about that.
-要打开这个？  -是
-Undo these.     -Yeah.
-好了        -嗯，谢谢
-Okay, now.  -Yeah, thanks.
好了
All right.
还有什么要帮忙的就跟我说
Well, just let me know if you need anything else.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安
Night.
很抱歉昨晚给你添麻烦了
I'm sorry for getting you in trouble last night.
没事，老朋友了
That's all right.  That's what old friends are for.
还好，她早上去上班的时候你还在睡
You're just lucky you were asleep when she left for work this morning.
我懂
I see.
你为什么要去伍德伯里
Yeah. So why do you wanna go to Woodbury?
我觉得那里应该有人知道那个女婴的来历
Well, I think there's somebody who might know  who that baby girl is.
你还记得我们学校的Scott Davis吗？
Do you remember Scott Davis from school?
恩，我记得
Yeah, I remember him.
他的妈妈，在我出生前是我们家厨师
His mom, Abbey, used to cook for my mom and dad back before I was born.
明白，我带你过去，希望她还住在那儿
Well, if she's still alive,I'll take you there.
打扰了，先生，Abigail Davis住这吗？
Excuse me, sir.Abigail Davis live here?
谢谢
Thank you.
Davis夫人？
Mrs. Davis?
嘿，Davis夫人？
Hey, Mrs. Davis.
我以前经常和你儿子Scott一起上学
I used to go to school with your son, Scott.
我是Preston.记得我吗？
It's Preston.Remember me?
我小时候经常和Scott一起玩
Me and Scott used to play together when we were little.
你经常骂我们不要顽皮从车库上跳下来，记得吗？
You used to yell at us for jumping off your garage. Remember?
Preston Saunders.
你在这摔得要死
You're gonna break your arm up there,
把我乐坏了
and I'm gonna laugh my ass off.
很开心又见到你了，Davis夫人，久别了
It's good to see you, Mrs. Davis.It's been a long time.
还有一位来看你.她是Jessie.Jessie Laurent.
There's someone else here to see you. This is Jessie.Jessie Laurent.
你经常给她做饭
You used to cook for her folks.
Jessie Laurent?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
Jessabelle!
Davis夫人
Mrs. Davis.
天，她还好吗？
God, is she all right?
刚她说了些什么？
What did she say?
不知道
I don't know.
她说:"暴雨淋透我们，妈妈"
She say,"Rain wet us, Mama.
“烈日晒干我们，爸爸"
"Sun dried us, Papa.
“这个邪恶的背叛者"
"The betrayers are evil.
“快叫Djowou来对付他们”
"Call down Djowou.
Call down Djowou
will deal with them."
是什么意思？
What's that mean?
是一首海地的古老歌谣
It's an old song from Haiti.
让灵魂附身某人才会吟唱
They sing it to call the spirits to possess someone.
告诉Moses Jessabelle她会得到她应得的！
Tell Moses Jessabelle get what's coming to her!
没事吧？
You okay?
这些愚昧的巫术
Goddamn voodoo shit.
我一直很讨厌Scott的妈妈
I always hated Scott's mom.
Jessie，别担心.她只是一个疯婆子
Jessie, don't worry. It's just some crazy old lady.
从头都到尾都在胡言乱语
Probably says shit like that all the time.
“让灵魂附身某人”到底是什么意思？
What does that mean "they call the spirits to get possessed"?
故意让灵魂附身吗？
On purpose?
也许在迷信的巫术看来不是件坏事
Well, yeah.In voodoo, possession ain't a bad thing.
什么？
What?
也许是他们仪式的部分内容
Yeah, it's part of their ceremonies.
就是他们祈求灵魂附到你身上
You call down the spirits, and they possess you,
然后开始跳舞之类的，他们一直那样
and you dance around.That's what they do.
你怎么知道这些？
How do you know that?
得了吧，你也在这长大啊，难道你不知道这里巫术横行？
Come on You grew up here, too. There's voodoo all around this place.
那真的会被附身吗？
They really get possessed?
那取决于你问谁.我觉得就是催眠一类的东西
Well, that depends on who you ask.I think it's like hypnosis.
就像信仰疗法，忽悠人的
You know,like faith-healing,speaking in tongues.
如果你被忽悠得信了
If you're raised to believe that,
就会觉得是真的
that's what you're gonna think is real.
加上敲锣打鼓，搞一堆人在旁边跳舞
Plus they've got drums going,people dancing around.
再涂点血在你身上.你就会觉得自己被附身了
They rub blood on you.You think you're possessed.
"Moses",她说过"去找Moses"
"Moses".She said, "Tell Moses."
那我就不知道了，巫术混合了很多宗教，天主教，非洲的各种教
I don't know.Voodoo mixes all kinds of religions, Catholic, African.
对他们而言都一样
It's all the same to them.
不，她说的是我妈妈认识的那个Moses.她在录影带里面提到过
No, my mom knew a Moses. She said that on the tape.
她在教会跟Moses学过塔罗牌
She learned tarot cards from Moses at her church.
我觉得教堂就在Jerry's Creek附近
I think her church was somewhere out near Jerry's Creek.
妈的
God damn it.
好的，你终于有机会见识我的专属大招“真·175度大转弯”了
Well, I guess you get to see my patented 175-point turn.
别，等等.那是什么？
No, wait, wait, wait.What's that?
"Moses哈勃。生于1952年12月12日
"Moses Harper.Born December 12th, 1952.
"死于1988年6月12日"
"Died June 12th, 1988."
"Legba,开门. Legba,让Moses回来"
"Legba, open the gate. Legba, let Moses back in."
滚开
Get out.
我是Preston，这是我朋友...
I'm Preston.This here is my friend...
-走吧Preston.         -我们不想惹麻烦
-Let's go, Preston.  -Look, now, we don't want any trouble.
嘿！别这样！
Hey! Stop it!
等等
Wait!
- Preston,你还好吗？     - 滚!
- Preston, you all right?- Go!
你不会是要回来住吧.
You're not coming back here.
这不是办法
Ever. There's no way.
Preston...
你不要住在这儿
You're not gonna stay here.
进去拿点要用的东西,然后去那我那住
You go in.Get whatever you need.You can stay with us again.
你老婆会怒的
Your wife's gonna be thrilled about that.
你可以住我妈那儿
You could stay at my mom's.
你知道的，我妈一直很喜欢你
My mom always liked you.You know that.
她还留着我们舞会时拍的照片
She's still got our prom pictures up.
这也就是Sam这么讨厌你的原因
That's another reason why Sam's so crazy about you.
她知道我心里还有你
She knows I still think about you.
她也知道我们很可能继续走到一起
And she knows we're probably gonna move on.
你不必那样做Jessie，只是现在你得做正确的事
But you didn't do it, Jessie.Not you showing up right now.
因为现在是非常时期
It's just weird timing is all.
好了，我带你离开这儿
All right. I'm gonna get you out of here.
好了吗？
Ready?
恩
Yeah.
恕我
Excuse me.
好了，我去准备你的行李
All right,let's get you packed.
你知道袋子在哪吗？
Would you grab me that bag?
恩
Yeah.
-给.      -谢谢
-Here you go. -Thank you.
我在旁边等着
I'll get this over here.
Preston?
好了，我们回吧
All right.Be right back.
-你好了吗？  -好了
-You ready? -All right.
Preston?
Oh! Preston!
你男朋友被吓到了，但他血压还正常
Your boyfriend is in shock, but his blood pressure is okay.
他应该没事
He should be fine when he comes to,
不过安全起见，还是把他送到了医院
but they're running him to the hospital just to be safe.
他不是我的男朋友.我们只是高中以来的朋友
He's not my boyfriend.  We were just friends from high school.
Laurent小姐,你能告诉我到底发生了什么吗？
Miss Laurent,do you mind telling me what the hell's going on here?
DNA检测结果还没出来
We don't have the results back on the DNA yet.
找到的那个婴儿是女性
But that infant we found,we do know was a female.
墓碑上的日期大概也是对的
The date on her gravestone was probably about right.
那么她是胎死腹中？
Well, then was she a stillborn?
不，她不是.她生下来了
No, she wasn't.She was born alive.They know that.
她是被谋杀的
Then she was murdered.
什么？
What?
从她骨折状况来看
From the nature of the fractures
脊椎骨完全断开
and the splintering of the vertebrae,
就像人有人把她举起来
it seems like somebody just picked her up
然后撞到膝盖上，这过程像是折断一根柴火
and snapped her over his knee like a piece of firewood.
她是被谋杀的
She was murdered.
Laurent小姐.我不知道这到底发生了什么
Miss Laurent, I don't know what the hell is going on around here,
但很明显，你很害怕.
but clearly,you are one very frightened young woman.
她并没有要伤害我们
She doesn't want to hurt us.
什么？
What?
她再寻求我们的帮助
She needs our help.
-谁？-呃...
-Who?-Uh...
警官，Preston醒来以后告诉我好吗？
Sheriff, would you mind calling me when Preston wakes up, please?
行
All right.
确认他好了后请务必通知我.
Please call me  when you know he's all right.
行
All right.
我知道你是被谋杀的
I know you were murdered.
你到底想告诉我什么？
What are you trying to tell me?
你曾是谁？
Who were you?
拜托，我想帮你
Please,I wanna help you.
你是谁？
Who are you?
Jessabelle.
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
Hello? Hello?
我是Pruitt警官.你男朋友已经来了
It's Sheriff Pruitt. Your boyfriend's come to.
他看起来好了.这是你想知道的
He seems all right.I thought you'd wanna know.
哦，他好了吗？
Oh, he's all right?
护理说他需要休息
The paramedics said he should rest.
但他不想再去医院了
He won't even go to the hospital for an exam.
他让我带他回你的房子
He wants me to take him back out to the house
去保护你之类
to protect you from something.
清楚了吗？那是什么？
Do you know what that is?
警官，我听不见你说什么.
Sheriff, I can barely hear you.
Laurent小姐,我们刚也得到DNA检测结果了
Miss Laurent, we also just got the results back from the DNA test.
那个死掉的女婴挖出来的是黑色的
That deceased baby girl that you dug up was black.
你在说什么？她是黑色的？
What did you say?She was black?
我不懂什么意思.是说她是我同母异斧的姐妹吗？
I don't understand.Does that mean she was my half-sister?
她跟你的DNA和你父亲Leon的不匹配...
They crossed your DNA with your father's,with Leon's...
什么？
What?
你在哭
That's you crying.
你在哭是因为你害怕
You're crying'cause you're scared.
你不知道你在哪.也不知道你是谁
You don't know where you are.You don't know who you are.
你他妈什么都不知道!
You don't know shit!
我来告诉你是谁
I'm gonna tell you who you are.
这是一个好母亲该做的
Because that's what good mothers do.
Jessabelle, 你已经死了.
Jessabelle, you're dead.
你的父亲也死了.
Your father's dead.
Moses.
一切都会好起来得，不是吗？
No, it's all gonna be all right, isn't it?
我需要你,甜心.我需要你,好孩子.
I need you, sugar.I need you. Good girl.
你会回来的，我会为你打开门等你
You're gonna come back.I'm gonna hold the door open for you.
Jessabelle,你会得到属于你的！
Jessabelle,you're gonna get what's coming to you!
你就是那个在房里多余的鬼魂？
The unwanted presence in the house.
你看到的鬼魂受伤了，对吗？
When you see it,it's broken, right?
那不是鬼魂.那就是我
It wasn't the ghost. It was me.
你跟我诉说的是其他人的命运对吗？
You were telling someone else's fortune,weren't you?
你知道它的预言是什么？它说你不会离开圣弗朗西斯
You know what it says here? It says that you've never left St. Francis
而且你永远不会离开
and that you're never gonna leave.
说的是你真正的女儿,而不是我
Your real daughter,not me.
你把自己的生命给了Jessabelle
You gave your life for Jessabelle.
不去做化疗
Didn't do chemo.
出生的孩子
When the baby was born,
不是爸爸的
it wasn't Dad's.
不,不！
No, no!
他杀了她,对吗？
He killed her,didn't he?
Moses教了我该怎么读牌
Moses taught me how to read cards.
看啊
Look at those.
别告诉爸爸.他会杀了我
Don't tell Dad. He'd kill me.
所以Leon用另一个女婴来掩盖这起犯罪？
So Leon adopted a baby girl to cover the crime?
一个白人女孩,就是我
A white girl, me.
你的教会,Moses的教会
Your church, Moses' church.
滚开
Get out.
把她埋葬了
They gave her the grave.
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
到底要我做什么？
What can I do?
Moses
Moses.
你们要干什么？
What are you doing?
还给我们
Payback.
什么？
What?
不！不.
No! No.
这不是我的错！
It's not my fault!
来人啊！
Somebody!
救命
Help!
不！你们到底要什么？
No! What do you want from me?
Jessabelle想要回她的一切
All Jessabelle wants is what's coming to her.
来人啊！不！不！
Somebody! No! No!
让我走！
Let me go!
这是....不,不,不！
What is... No, no, no!
不！
No!
求你不要
Please don't.
你要带我去哪？
Where are you taking me?
不,神啊!救我
No, God! Please.
求你
Please!
Jessie!
救命
Please! Help me!
不！天啊
No! God!
哦，我的天！抓住.抓住.
Oh, my God! Hold on. Hold on.
你没事吧？
You all right?
我还以为失去你了呢.
I thought I lost you.
带我回去，亲爱的
Take me home, my love.
Laurent小姐？你没事吧？
Miss Laurent? Are you all right?
Laurent小姐!
Miss Laurent!
是Jessabelle
It's Jessabelle.